Qiuming (Vera) Wei

Address:

205-928 Richards St Vancouver, B.C V68 6P6

Contact:

vera.wqm@gmail.com (778) 866 - 8046

Social:

- Github
- LinkedIn
- Blog

TECHNICAL STACK

• Front End: JavaScript, React (7 years), Redux, TypeScript, Jest, Backbone, ES5/6/7, Less/ Sass/CSS Modules/ PostCSS, Tailwind, Storybook

• Server & Back End:

NodeJs, NestJs, RESTful API, GraphQL, K8s, Docker, Kafka, Vercel, PHP, Java

- Cloud & Database: MS Azure, Alibaba Cloud, GCP, Firebase, MySQL, MongoDB
- Tools: Git, Webpack, Gulp, NPM, Yarn, CI/CD, Mixpanel, Segment,

"Vera is dedicated to providing quality work. She checks and rechecks her project before turning it in for presentation to the final users. She strives to make her programs as user friendly as possible understanding that not everyone is an expert programmer."

 Amos Chen Sr Staff Engineer Manager at Alibaba

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An enthusiastic software engineer with a decade of professional experience including several years focused in full stack. Possessing comprehensive skills in all aspects of development with expertise spanning multiple industries, including marketing and advertising, enterprise collaboration, Internet of Things, and automation testing. Well-versed in Agile engineering practices, utilizing them to foster efficient and collaborative development processes.

EDUCATION

- Post Degree Diploma, Douglas College, Vancouver, BC, Canada 2019 2020 Information Communication & Technology
- Bachelor of Science, Nanjing Tech University, Nanjing, China 2009 2013 Computer Science

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Full Stack Engineer @ Sauce Labs Inc., Jan. 2021 - May 2023 (2 years 4 months) Growth team member for a continuously testing company, collaborating across teams to deliver new experimental features using Agile development practices.

• Sauce Labs (web app + signup)

- Employed NextJS to construct a user-friendly sign-up process for new users, resulting in improved product activation and accelerated value realization
- Coordinated user identification and tracking using Segment across products and documentation websites, leveraging Mixpanel and Pendo for usage analytics to inform future decision-making
- Created REST APIs and services using NodeJS and Kafka for Growth microservice, facilitating user registration and analysis of user traits and actions to enhance the quality of sales leads
- Spearheaded the implementation of feature flags for A/B experiments and rapid prototyping, leading to measured successes and widespread adoption throughout the organization
- Optimized the CI/CD pipeline to reduce 60% of the running time
- Created a plugin Platform configurator component for reuse in different locations
- Supported the testing script generator with different languages (Python, JavaScript, Ruby, C#, etc.)

• Sauce Labs Website

- Wrote a node script to migrate 1000+ articles from the original site
- Collaborated closely with the marketing team to develop the corporate website using React and Contentful (CMS), resulting in improved user sign-up quality
- Utilized Vercel practices for deployment and monitoring

Senior Software Engineer @ Alibaba Cloud, Aug. 2017 - Sep. 2019 (2 years)

Served in a prominent global company, contributing as a client-facing engineer. Provided mentorship, assisting junior engineers in skill development, tool utilization, and best practices and successfully guiding at least 5 developers towards promotion through effective coaching.

IoT Studio

• Led engineering teams and implemented 20+ graph/diagram/Text etc. virtualized components with a dynamic data stream, connecting the client-side with base-level cloud services

"It was a pleasure working with Vera on a daily basis. She likes to deeply understand business problems she is dealing with and does not hesitate to share ideas how to make the solution even better. Vera is a good connector and definitely a people person she was a key factor to deal with dependencies efficiently and exchanging the knowledge between teams (including non-engineering ones). I admire Vera's dedication to constant selfdevelopment and curiosity about what's happening in tech and beyond."

> — Andrzej Figas Director of Engineering at Sauce Labs

"Vera impressed me with not only her 'student for life' mindset, but also her amazingly positive attitude and communication skills. Vera is the kind of employee I would hire again with no hesitation."

> Huaqiao Li
> Staff Software Engineer at Teambition

"She takes her work very seriously, and was always striving to stay on top of the latest development in the field of Front-End development. Vera performs well under stress and tight deadlines, and I would wholeheartedly recommend her."

Lucia Lu
 Front-end Dev at
 Fancy Pants Group

- Designed and implemented a long-channel solution based on the MQTT protocol to solve real-time communication problems between IoT devices. Handled different edge cases, such as building reconnection or destroying mechanisms
- Outlined specifications and actively on call to respond to user feedback

• ICA Data Platform

- Organized technical system design meetings to complete the whole chain in every development lifecycle
- Led teams to develop and provide capabilities for creating things templates, attributes, services, events, and source modules for partners. Connected specific customers (developers) with Alibaba Cloud's fundamental technical capabilities like virtual devices, service modeling, etc. in order to help them to sell their solutions

Consoles

- Managed teams and implemented several consoles from scratch to release to production environment
- · Took responsibility for the growth of junior engineers as well as product quality
- Led redesign of a solution and developed a npm plugin to efficiently extract and replace characters from antiquated projects for Localization/Globalization purposes. Reduced workload from 10 people per day to 1 person per day and achieved concrete goals on a strict deadline

Senior Front-End Developer @ Teambition, Sep. 2015 - Jul. 2017 (1 year 10 months)

Recruited to top enterprise collaboration platform to build single-page web application. Began mastering React and related skills from this point forward.

Teambition

- Implemented Gantt chart view in the project panel. Enhanced users to create tasks in virtual drag-drops. Applied accurate calculations of users' view size to streamline pagination loading
- Integrated Chinese social platforms for use as users' third-party accounts.
 Implemented sequence diagrams and designed various user cases to overcome differences between two account structures and API requirements
- Leveraged sophisticated experience with data caching system design, such as cookie, local/session storage etc.
- Improved overall performance by 70% (decreasing first-page loading time from 5.2s to 4s) by replacing image assets with sprite, applying lazy loading, and using SSR (Server-side Rendering) for some static pages. Replaced most react components with pure and functional components

• Annual User Review

 Started from conceptualization and designed an implementation solution which translated a smooth animation design into a dynamic mobile first animation with GreenSockJs in 3 days for yearly reuse

Web Developer @ Fancy Pants Group, Mar. 2013 - Jun. 2015 (2 years 4 months)

Specialized in creating detail-orientated webpages for marketing and advertising. Extensive training in advanced HTML/CSS/Javascript skills as a web developer.

• Online dynamic HTM5 animations

- Created responsive and adaptive webpages across different devices, adjusting for diverging viewport sizes, resolutions, usage contexts, and control mechanisms
- Delivered more than 50 projects with strong UI/UX skills
- Worked with most animation solutions (css3 animation, Canvas, WebGL, SVG)
- Utilized several popular animation libraries, eg. GreenSock, ThreeJs, D3, etc.
- Designed several downgrade solutions for older browsers (IE8, Android 2.x, etc.)